<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on The Adventures of Arran Short</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The Adventures of Arran Short</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arranshort.xyz/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Goodbye Ghost, Hello Hugo</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/goodbye-ghost-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/goodbye-ghost-hello-hugo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m finding myself limited to when and how I can post and ghost just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to suit my needs anymore.
I&amp;rsquo;m happy working from the cli or github to create posts plus github actions handles deploy on push.
Great success!
Heres to posting more this year and less sysadamin LOL</description></item><item><title>Getting the cogs turning for My Open Source Engine ECU</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/starting-my-open-source-engine-ecu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 22:52:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/starting-my-open-source-engine-ecu/</guid><description>After moving my TMS750 development kit from box to box I&amp;rsquo;ve recently decided to see if there had been any community progress on getting the hardware angle clock (HWAG) working.
The tl;dr seems to be that a few have tried but came up against a possible hardware bug making it practically useless. I&amp;rsquo;ve even asked on the TI forums for example code but they don&amp;rsquo;t have any.
My aim for this ECU is to have a fully open source, highly versatile and precise base to be used on affordable hardware.</description></item><item><title>Finding the ultimate IoT Hub</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/finding-the-ultimate-iot-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/finding-the-ultimate-iot-hub/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a Samsung SmartThings v2 Hub for about two years now but before it goes the way of the DoDo or a surprise subscription appears out of nowhere that I&amp;rsquo;m forced to use as I&amp;rsquo;ve invested too much in custom rules.
Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve set out to find a replacement hub that will work with Home Assistant and isn&amp;rsquo;t reliant on &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo; and runs an open source OS, Ideally Linux.</description></item><item><title>Managing Multiple Kubernetes Clusters easily with konfig and kubectx</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/managing-multiple-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 11:33:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/managing-multiple-kubernetes/</guid><description>At work I&amp;rsquo;ve been setting up a few Kubernetes clusters for AWX, Vault and other fancy tools.
Getting helm and the like working with k3s and managing it all nicely with kubectl has been a bit of a faff to say the least.
I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at kubectl context before but it hadn&amp;rsquo;t sunk in how to manage it all.
In comes konfig and kubectx:
Konfig
This can be installed via krew ( a kubectl plugin manager ) and the awesome piece of software allows you to easily manage your .</description></item><item><title>CAN to USB on a budget with Nucleo-f072rb part 1</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/can-to-usb-on-a-budget-with-nucleo-f072rb-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 14:30:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/can-to-usb-on-a-budget-with-nucleo-f072rb-part-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking to get back into CANbus hacking but all my USB to CAN boards are a bit of a bodge and after recently wasting an evening trying to get one to work again I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I want to scrap everything and start again with a known good USB to CAN tool that does the job everytime.
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen various boards crop up on hackaday but most just emulate the lawciel serial protocol so consistancy at high bus load isn&amp;rsquo;t great.</description></item><item><title>open5xxxecu.org</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/open5xxxecu-org/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 10:22:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/open5xxxecu-org/</guid><description>So I noticed that this domain has been left to expire as the project hasn&amp;rsquo;t really taken off.
With RusEFI and Speeduino getting traction it seems there is still interest for an open ECUs but nothing is really covering the higher end ECU market.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at starting my own OSEK/AUTOSAR based open ECU using the Erika RTOS but haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on what hardware is best to use.
I&amp;rsquo;ve got my eye on the following CPUs</description></item><item><title>Return of the fifth</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/return-of-the-fifth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 17:08:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/return-of-the-fifth/</guid><description>I got bored of getting downtime emails from the freehosting.com proxy so I&amp;rsquo;ve coughed up for a contabo.com vps server.
Now on Ghost 2.x - docker and Traefik doing the reverse proxy and SSL eventually.</description></item><item><title>Back for the 4th time..</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/back-for-the-4th-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/back-for-the-4th-time/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll get this right eventually.
I&amp;rsquo;m now running the blog on an Openshift Starter account proxied via php hosted on a freehosting.com cpanel account.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing a small review of Openshift Starter soon.</description></item><item><title>My Bad...</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/my-bad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/my-bad/</guid><description>The blog has been away for a while, mostly as I foolishly ran a docker rm -f * on my server while trying to remove a broken kubernetes install.
Regardless it&amp;rsquo;s back and on a 3 node rancher kubernetes cluster.</description></item><item><title>LibreElec running on the ASUS Tinker Board ( KODI )</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/libreelec-running-on-the-asus-tinker-board-kodi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 12:19:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/libreelec-running-on-the-asus-tinker-board-kodi/</guid><description>Yep you&amp;rsquo;ve read that correctly the ASUS Tinkerboard has finally had some LibreElec lovin'
Omegamoon has forked LibreElec and added all the necessary patches and tools to build a bootable SD card image of LibreElec for the ASUS tinker board.
You can find the fork here https://github.com/omegamoon/LibreELEC.tv/tree/Rockchip And the guide I followed to build it here https://wiki.libreelec.tv/index.php?title=Compile
Progress
LEDs (power, sd-card activity and heartbeat) Persistent ethernet MAC-address set in u-boot Kodi fbdev (for performance testing, no vsync, no double buffering) Kodi DRM/KMS Basic rendering Resolution / refresh rate change Atomic DRM Audio I2S Stereo L-PCM I2S Multi-channel L-PCM I2S NL-PCM (AC3/E-AC3/DTS) I2S/SPDIF HBR (TrueHD/DTS-HD) HDA 3.</description></item><item><title>ASUS Tinker Board - TinkerOS 1.4</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/asus-tinker-board-tinkeros-1-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 15:59:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/asus-tinker-board-tinkeros-1-4/</guid><description>Asus have recently released version 1.4 of TinkerOS which is their flavour of Debian for the tinker board.
This is the list of changes taken from their website.
1. Enable hardware acceleration for Chromium Web Browser. * Please also download chrome plug in “h264ify” to have best performance 2. Improve the system stability. 3. Fix keyboard/mouse repeating event issue. 4. Preload Synaptic. I did notice a fairly decent increase in boot speed and also I can confirm that the annoying keyboard issue is resolved Yee haw!</description></item><item><title>BMW 1 series F20 iDrive controller hacking with arduino and PI</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/bmw-1-series-f20-idrive-controller/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/bmw-1-series-f20-idrive-controller/</guid><description>As part of a larger in car entertainment project, I needed a simple and safe input method to control the software that wasn’t a touch screen. As BMWs are popular in the car PC scene I thought I’d buy an IDrive controller as surely there will be an Arduino lib to get it working.
Nope, there are a few pages of people giving out tiny bits of information or claiming to have done it but haven’t shared it on the Web.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with the ASUS Tinker board... or not!</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/getting-started-with-asus-tinker-board/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/getting-started-with-asus-tinker-board/</guid><description>Google Now pointed me to some blog posts about a newly released SBC to compete with the raspberry pi, the ASUS Tinker board.
The Specs of ASUS Tinker board sound good on paper but I guess the proof is in the pudding.  I have made a quick unboxing video and wanted to follow up with my initial thoughts but I’m stuck at the first hurdle, I can’t find any software!</description></item><item><title>DIY 50mil (1.27mm) to 100mil (2.54mm) adapter for atatmel ice</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/ive-been-meaning-to-try-new-cortex-m0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/ive-been-meaning-to-try-new-cortex-m0/</guid><description>I’ve been meaning to try the new cortex m0 chips by atmel but was put off by the high programmer price, fortunately, they now sell a bare version known as atatmel-ice-pcba with no case or cables. So after the initial shock of how small the cortex debug connector is I set off to find a cheap way to break this out to 0.1″ headers.
Fortunately a soic chip has the same footprint as the SMD variant of the mating connector.</description></item><item><title>Using the TPLink TL-POE10R PoE Splitter with a Cisco Inline power switch WS-C3550-24PWR-SMI</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/using-tplink-tl-poe10r-poe-splitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/using-tplink-tl-poe10r-poe-splitter/</guid><description>TL:DR using some relays to bridge the Tx and Rx pins on the “normally closed” pins so that it go open circuit when powered is enough to enable the power output and it works no problem with a TL-POE10R
As part of my Raspberry Pi Zero CCTV project, I’ve opted to use PoE to get data and power outside to the cameras.
After another hasty ebay spree, I ended up with a Cisco WS-C3550-24PWR-SMI 24 port “PoE” switch.</description></item><item><title>Technika Freeview 8320HD box hacking</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/technika-freeview-8320hd-box-hacking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/technika-freeview-8320hd-box-hacking/</guid><description>I’ve had this sat on a shelf for a few years in the hope I can one day get root on this device and have it multicast the dvb-t2 streams over the network.
I’ve crawled the internet to find what info is about for this and there doesn’t seem to be a publicly know way to get root.
My first port of call is to removed the BGA flash chip and try and read this with some sort of DIY nand reader.</description></item><item><title>Hummingboard i2 &amp; Motorola lapdock 720p fix.</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hummingboard-i2-motorola-lapdock-720p/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hummingboard-i2-motorola-lapdock-720p/</guid><description>I bought a Hummingboard i2 off ebay as it was going cheap and I’ve wanted to play with an sbc with canbus and lvds.
Anyway it came with openelec on the memory card so to test it I connected it up to my to my lapdock and getto usb cable.
Kodi loaded but it would only give 720x576p resolution.
Turns out any none standard resolutions given over edid are ignored by the kernel and it defaults to 576p.</description></item><item><title>Teensy 3.1 with working flexCAN interrupts and BUSMASTER compatibility</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/teensy-31-with-working-flexcan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 14:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/teensy-31-with-working-flexcan/</guid><description>The Teensy 3.1 flexCAN library doesn’t have the facility for setting up interrupts for incoming messages. So I set out to fix the problem, and after a lot of forum research and a few tweaks I’ve been able to get interrupts working.
I’ve ported my mcp2515 based Arduino CAN to USB logger to the Teensy, this firmware implements the Lawicel protocol (badly haha) to be compatible with canhacker software.
While doing a bit of research I discovered that VScom’s ser-com tool also uses the Lawicel protocol and they have drivers built into Bosch’s BUSMASTER software, WINNER!</description></item><item><title>STM32F103xC + ILI9341 LCD + FSMC + CHIBiOS + UGFX = Success! - CC9060 hacking Part 2</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/stm32f103xc-ili9341-lcd-fsmc-chibios/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/stm32f103xc-ili9341-lcd-fsmc-chibios/</guid><description>After re writing the ugfx board config from scratch and going through the code with a fine tooth comb I finally got the LCD to work!
The included drivers for the ILI9341 are only written for 8bit wiring configs, so I got an Image of sorts, but just in blue.
After reading every thread on the ugfx forum relating to the ILI9341 I found this one which explained what I need to do to get the other 8 bits back.</description></item><item><title>Resurrecting the Sony Ericsson Live View MN800</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/resurrecting-sony-ericsson-live-view/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 17:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/resurrecting-sony-ericsson-live-view/</guid><description>Another STM32 I’ve had for years is the Liveview.
A few clever people on the XDA developers forum have reverse engineered the device and made drivers for chibios.
The code is on github here —-&amp;gt; https://github.com/GottZ/olvfw FYI this is not my code!!
It’s old code but I’ve compiled it my self and flashed it and it works!
And yes I’ll be getting canbus working via the micro usb port at some point 🙂</description></item><item><title>Hacking the Bury CC9060 / VW Touch Phone Kit - Part 1</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hacking-bury-cc9060-vw-touch-phone-kit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hacking-bury-cc9060-vw-touch-phone-kit/</guid><description>Whilst looking for an LCD to use as a display for Megasquirt
I found a display from a Volkswagen Touch Phone kit, these are a VW themed and branded version of the Bury CC9060 The 708 version of this hardware has an STM32F103 with some nice little goodies left on the board from when it was being developed.
I’ve sacrificed one to work out the JTAG/SWD pinouts and to establish how the LCD is connected to the board.</description></item><item><title>Innovate MTS to Megasquirt CAN Bus converter part 1</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/innovate-mts-to-megasquirt-can-bus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/innovate-mts-to-megasquirt-can-bus/</guid><description>After quiting my job last month I’ve finally had some time to put my collection of STM32 boards to work.
With the addition of the STM32 cpus to the MBED platform its made it super simple to write code for them.
The first thing that I’ve decided to develop is an Innovate MTS to Megasquirt CANBUS converter.
You can see the MBED project here
https://developer.mbed.org/users/sordfish/code/MTS_TO_MSCAN/wiki/Homepage
Its still alpha code but I’ve had it connected to a Microsquirt and it was doing something!</description></item><item><title>Burg on Linux Mint 17.3</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/burg-on-linux-mint-173/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/burg-on-linux-mint-173/</guid><description>Santa dropped off an SSD for my dev laptop which duel boots windows xp and Linux mint. I’ve always wanted something a bit more polished for a boot manager and found Burg Brand-new Universal loadeR from GRUB
Here’s how I installed it
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:n-muench/burg sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install burg burg-themes sudo burg-install /dev/sda (please check the name of your drive) sudo update-burg Then to test
burg-emu ta da!</description></item><item><title>Open source TI Hercules LAUNCHXL2-TMS57012 based ECU</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/open-source-ti-hercules-launchxl2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/open-source-ti-hercules-launchxl2/</guid><description>Well I’ve finally found some free time to open my LaunchXL2 – TMS570 dev kit from TI.
Its always been a dream to have made my own ECU from scratch and after having my ear to the ground on what’s hot and what’s not hardware wise I’ve opted to go for a TI TMS570 cpu.
There are plenty of “open” ECUs at the moment but none have really excited me as their hardware isn’t really automotive grade or the dev kit is a high price tag or they are just buried in conflicting hardware designs.</description></item><item><title>Pushbullet Notification Mirroring on Xbmc</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/pushbullet-notification-mirroring-on/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/pushbullet-notification-mirroring-on/</guid><description>Pushbullet is an epic messaging service that allows Android notifications to be mirrored via their chrome plugin or pc app. Their api has just has an overhaul which included the ability to have 3rd party clients. I wanted to get my notifications mirrored to my tv so I set out to make a script for xbmc to do just that! its up on git hub here [https://github.com/sordfish/xbmc-pushbullet](https://github.com/sordfish/xbmc-pushbullet) just clone the repo rename the dir to script.</description></item><item><title>Converting Cheap HDMI switch to usb. with added php magic</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/converting-cheap-hdmi-switch-to-usb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/converting-cheap-hdmi-switch-to-usb/</guid><description>Finally got round to adding some usb goodness to a cheapy hdmi switch I got off ebay.it has 3 inputs and is controlled by a button in the center to choose which channel is active, it has auto detect but i tend not to switch anything off so thats useless, plus having to get out of bed once I’ve got comfy to change inputs was slighty 2001 so…[![]()]()out the goody box comes a minimus avr dev board i acquired of ebay fairly cheap, it has an at90usb162 mcu that can be [persuaded](http://www.</description></item><item><title>It lives!!!</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/it-lives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/it-lives/</guid><description>So after assembling the first 1 1/2 boards with a mixture of hot air and soldering iron (I love how the surface tension of the solder paste auto aligns everything up with hot air) and it turned out quite well. I’ve spotted a few “mistakes” on my part but nothing a revised board wouldn’t fix.. all part of the learning curve I guess.[![]() ]()[![]() ](http://lh6.ggpht.com/-UONUSGkSPkQ/UYQwq9qeDdI/AAAAAAAAAiY/wf80sckzvjg/s1600/20130424_164254.jpg)So the main purpose of these boards is to have a simple and low cost way to use canbus, for me this will be used with automotive projects.</description></item><item><title>My purple ser kit boreds have arrived!!!</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/my-purple-ser-kit-boreds-have-arrived/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 19:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/my-purple-ser-kit-boreds-have-arrived/</guid><description>Yee ha my boards came today, after battling with upverter to design the schematic and pcb (which actually is a pretty good design tool once you work around the quirks) I put an order in with oshpark.com.
Im glad I did as i cant get over how sexy the purple and gold looks in the flesh.
Ive spotted one mistake so far but nothing major and there might be a few fine lines with the ground fill not being thick enough.</description></item><item><title>Designing projects with Circuits.io and Upverter</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/designing-projects-with-circuitsio-and/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 22:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/designing-projects-with-circuitsio-and/</guid><description>I’ve been wanting to get into designing my own boards for projects and decided to give a cloud based system a go.
The idea is great but both systens are still very beta, lack of manuals and lots of crashing has put me off.
hopefully I can export my project and just bite the bullet with kicad. maybe it will take off in 12 months time.</description></item><item><title>Making the WR702n run openwrt part 1</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/making-wr702n-run-openwrt-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/making-wr702n-run-openwrt-part-1/</guid><description>After blindly buying a blue tplink router off eBay at 3am, it turns out I bought the WR702n instead of the openwrt friendly WR703n.
The wr702n runs vxworks and only has 2MB flash and 16MB ram and no USB, This isn’t enough for openwrt.
It turns out that other fellow hackers have upgraded the flash and ram on the 703 so I’v done the same to the WR702n.
Getting the Parts…</description></item><item><title>State of the Union</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/state-of-union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 03:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/state-of-union/</guid><description>Well its been nearly a whole year since my last post, which sucks but there has been some major things happen which have taken up most of my time.
First of all I got a job finally, Yay! working for Geek Squad in Carphone Warehouse, which was totally not what I expected but the job is great and I’ve nearly been there a year, and hope to stay a few more.</description></item><item><title>Woo my goodfet boards came!</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/woo-my-goodfet-boards-came/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/woo-my-goodfet-boards-came/</guid><description>Many thanks to Travis Goodspeed for posting some GoodFet41 boards to me, still not got all the parts yet [ skint 🙁 ] but here’s a few snaps of my semi assembled board, all hand soldered 😀
[![](http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3-x6SP1Bi2o/TaMMgarGfCI/AAAAAAAAAGY/foCzKgiz6UQ/s320/goodfet1.bmp)](http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3-x6SP1Bi2o/TaMMgarGfCI/AAAAAAAAAGY/foCzKgiz6UQ/s1600/goodfet1.bmp)[![](http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dc6WI3Msnog/TaMMmA7ELnI/AAAAAAAAAGc/jhfwVRkMzj0/s320/goodfet2.bmp)](http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dc6WI3Msnog/TaMMmA7ELnI/AAAAAAAAAGc/jhfwVRkMzj0/s1600/goodfet2.bmp)[![](http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZS12OxnV6Qk/TaMNOq3KweI/AAAAAAAAAGg/YVQeJcFevx0/s320/Picture1.jpg)](http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZS12OxnV6Qk/TaMNOq3KweI/AAAAAAAAAGg/YVQeJcFevx0/s1600/Picture1.jpg)</description></item><item><title>openwrt on Edimax NS-1500N working?</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/openwrt-on-edimax-ns-1500n-working/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 23:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/openwrt-on-edimax-ns-1500n-working/</guid><description>gWell I wasn’t expecting that to happen.
I thought I’d try the fon 2.0n openwrt build environment on it as they are similar chips, anways I messed around with kernel configs abit and seemed I broke something so I had to manually select setting, so I picked rt3050 options and proper memory size an hey presto a stock fon2.0n flashed fine :Owifi and usb all seem to work, next is how to remove all the fon branding etc.</description></item><item><title>Change of plans?</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/change-of-plans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/change-of-plans/</guid><description>Had a tiny bit more progress on the zoom, managed to dump the firmware, and now I’ve been able to distinguish the header and checksums, all the info will be documented in a wiki once working.
Also another ebay bargin an Edimax NS-1500N, this listed on their site as a wireless NAS but has an RT3050.
This thing is tiny! its like 1/2 the size of the zoom. its listed as having 4MB flash on the edimax site but Amazingly it seems to have 8MB of flash inside :O so I’ll be moving focus to that.</description></item><item><title>Hacking Zoom 4501 part 2.5</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hacking-zoom-4501-part-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hacking-zoom-4501-part-25/</guid><description>while randomly searching ebay for bargin rt305x devices i spotted a LEVEL ONE WBR-6800 which looks very familiar to the zalip CDW530AM…
Found the manufactures website and hey presto its the same and there’s a gpl zip for it.
Followed the instructions that came with it and make fails, it seems a lot has bee stripped out, but I’ve spotted the make file and program that builds the firmware.
I’ve also had reply from zoom with a link for gpl stuff and it look like it has come from the same place (amit) but dated older so fingers crossed that compiles.</description></item><item><title>Hacking zoom 4501 part 2</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hacking-zoom-4501-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/hacking-zoom-4501-part-2/</guid><description>I emailed zoom for sources and got the response “sorry- this is not possible.” so unless they miss understood the email they are violating gpl by not releasing it., noobs.Any way it seems it is also known as Aluratek CDW530AM and Zalip CDW530AM, I’ve downloaded some firmware for the aluratek model to see if I could flash that.
They have different headers but even after changing that the zoom router wouldn’t accept the firmware.</description></item><item><title>ECU interface using Openwrt on Zoom 4501. Part 1</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/ecu-interface-using-openwrt-on-zoom/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/ecu-interface-using-openwrt-on-zoom/</guid><description>I’ve been seeing the increase of Iphone integration with cars recently, most notably the generic OBD2 wifi/bluetooth interfaces and the accompanying apps.
This got me thinking, can it be done for pre obd2 or standalone ecus. I had a look at target devices that would suit and the only cross-platform connection they had that was reliable is wifi.
Now most ecus use a USB connection so I set out to find hardware with wifi and a USB host port, and came across affordable 3g wifi routers.</description></item><item><title>Arduino + canbus + megasquirt = win.</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/arduino-canbus-megasquirt-win/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/arduino-canbus-megasquirt-win/</guid><description>Well few weeks ago I had another look at getting my arduino and an mcp2515 to play nice, not knowing where to start I had a search to see if anyone had made a lib that was easy to understand and found [canduino](http://code.google.com/p/canduino/). Had a play with that and after a few emails back and forth to the owner I had some response from the 2515 Yay!The next task was to configure the chip to receive messages so after reading the datasheet and the megasquirt can docs 500 times I got a response from the MS2.</description></item><item><title>DIY SOIC 20 TO DIP 20...</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/diy-soic-20-to-dip-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/diy-soic-20-to-dip-20/</guid><description>Hats off to TI ordered my TPIC8101 sample and it turned up in less than a week..
As I’m impatient and broke I thought I’d have a go at making my own SOIC TO DIP adapter
so I can easily attach it to my arduino..
Here&amp;rsquo;s a few pics!
Pics are M.I.A will fix soon</description></item><item><title>Winter electronic projects...</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/winter-electronic-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/winter-electronic-projects/</guid><description>Finally I’ve got a s2000 cluster to play with, So my mission is to get my Arduino to get that working pretty with the old honda sensors, should be fun as they look sick!
I’ve ordered a few samples of the TPIC8101 knock sensor interface as I fancy getting that to work as I’m after a decent knock monitor that isn’t a piss take price wize.
Hack a day had a link to a competition for designing stuff with a stm32 cortex 3 arm bla bla and for entering you supposedly get a free stm32 dev board so will see if that turns up, should work well with the knock chip.</description></item><item><title>This week I have been mostly doing...</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/this-week-i-have-been-mostly-doing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/this-week-i-have-been-mostly-doing/</guid><description>Very little.
My pos Civic is back in its spot on the drive! Hopefully once I get it running (only need to fit the tank, battery and finish up the loom). I’ve also order a 128×64 glcd to replace the temp and fuel gauge and try to pull data from the stock ecu.My sample order from microchip finally came so I can start messing around with my arduino and canbus. been trying to find examples how to use it but they all seem to use a lib that some German guy wrote and at the moment its way over my head :S.</description></item><item><title>Puma turbo goes 12.8 @ 116 MPH</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/puma-turbo-goes-128-116-mph/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 12:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/puma-turbo-goes-128-116-mph/</guid><description>My good friend Lewis has shoehorned a Zetec turbo into a Ford Puma.
I’ve done all the wiring on the car including fitting and mapping a Megasquirt ecu.
It went to pod last weekend (17/04) and managed a best time of 12.8 on its first outing!
It&amp;rsquo;s still on stock suspension so there is plenty of potential left and still needs dyno time.</description></item><item><title>Megasquirt and Arduino</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/megasquirt-and-arduino/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/megasquirt-and-arduino/</guid><description>After playing with my Nokia 770, and getting pissed off with python I’ve gone back to making an Arduino display data on 20×4 lcd.
I’m a noob at coding with an Arduino but I’m finding it easier to pick up and I’ve managed to get it working pretty reasonably.
I’ve bought some parts from bobsbits.co.uk to make an arduino shield for my lcd and fit it all in my project box, as its spaghetti at the moment.</description></item><item><title>Megasquirt on nokia 770</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/megasquirt-on-nokia-770/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 12:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/megasquirt-on-nokia-770/</guid><description>I was thinking the other day how good would it be to have some gauges and basic tuning abilities on the nokia 770 as its based on Linux and gtk I thought it shouldn’t be that hard to write something in python, but thought why start from scratch when there’s megatunix.I’ve had a tiny look into building it from source but it seems a chore just to even get scratchbox working.</description></item><item><title>First post...</title><link>https://arranshort.xyz/post/first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arranshort.xyz/post/first-post/</guid><description>I’ve had the blog for ages so may aswell keep a record of what I’ve been upto..</description></item></channel></rss>